A Guide to the James Branch Cabell Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #5947
James Branch Cabell Collection 1918-1956
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
5947
ca. 190 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1958 Nov 12
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Mar 7; TLS, 3 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Mar 23; TLS, 3 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Apr 1; TLS, 3 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/autograph postscript, 1918 Apr 9; TLS, 3 p.
  - "Procrustes" [ Burton Rascoe] to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Apr 18; TLS, 3 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1918] Apr 20; ANS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/autograph postscript, 1918 Apr 20; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/encl. transcript of TLS, 3 p., Burton Rascoe to Rupert Hughes, 1918 Apr 28; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/autograph postscript, 1918 Apr 25; TLS, 4 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1918 Apr]; ANS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 May 1; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1918] May 8; TLS, 6 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 May 12; TLS, 4 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 May 14; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 May 17; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 May 29; TLS, 3 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/autograph postscript, [1918 May]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Jun 25; TLS, 7 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Jul 24; TLS, 4 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Jul 31; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Aug 7; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Aug 17; TLS, 5 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Sep 1; TLS, 4 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1918] Sep 17; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Oct 9; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Oct 14; TLS, 3 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Oct 15; TLS, 5 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Oct 29; TLS, 2 p.
  - Mabel McElliott to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Nov 12; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/autograph postscript, 1918 Dec 31; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Jan 10; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Jan 13; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1919 Jan]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Jesse Quitman to Burton Rascoe, [1919 Jan]; TL, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to Jesse Quitman, [1919 Jan]; TL, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Feb 12; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1919 Feb]; ALS, 3 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Mar 5; TLS, 3 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Mar 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1919] Mar 24; ANS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1919 Mar]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1919 May 12; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Jun 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1919 Jun]; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/autograph postscript, 1919 Jul 18; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1919 Jul]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Aug 4; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Sep 15; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1919 Sep]; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1919 Sep]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Oct 20; TLS, 4 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Oct 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Nov 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Nov 12; TLS, 4 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Dec 23; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Dec 24; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1919 Dec]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1920 Jan 2; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1920 Jan 5; TLS, 7 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1920 Jan 23; TLS, 4 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1920 Feb 7; ALS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1920 Apr 19; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1920 May 2; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/autograph postscript, 1920 Oct 5; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/autograph postscript, 1920 Nov 20; TLS, 3 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1921 May 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Aug 17; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Sep 19; ALS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Oct 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Oct 25; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Nov 18; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Nov 22; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/autograph postscript, 1921 Dec 8; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Dec 8; ALS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/autograph postscript, 1922 Apr 18; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1922 May 18; ALS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Sep 11; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/autograph postscript, 1924 Jun 5; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Oct 7; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Oct 21; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1927 Mar 23; ANS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1927 Mar 23; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1927 Mar 29; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1927 Apr 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1927 May 2; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1927 May 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1927 May 31; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1927 Jun 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1927 Jun 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1927 Jul 2; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/autograph postscript, 1927 Jul 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1927 Jul 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1927 Sep 8; ALS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1927 Sep 22; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1927 Sep 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1928 Apr 29; ALS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1928]; APCS
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1929 Jan 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/autograph postscript, 1929 Mar 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1929 Mar 22; ALS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1929 Apr 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1929 May 15; APCS
  - Burton Rascoe to Mrs. James Branch Cabell, 1929 May 15; APCS
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1930 Jan 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1930 Jan 29; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1930 Feb 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1930 Mar 26; TNS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1930 Mar 31; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1930 Apr 2; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1930 Apr 5; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1930 Apr 25; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1930 May 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1930 Jun 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1930 Oct 6; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1932 Nov 30; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, signed for Rascoe, 1932 Dec 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1933 May 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1933 May]; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1933 Jul 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1933 Sep 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1933 Sep 28; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/autograph postscript, 1933 Dec 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1934 Mar 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1934 Jul 7; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1934]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1935 Sep 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1935 Oct 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1936 Mar 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1936 Mar 30; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/encl. 3 pp. transcript of TLS, April 18, Rupert Hughes to Rascoe, and 4 pp. TL (carbon), April 23, Rascoe to Hughes, 1936 Apr 24; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1936 May 16; Telegram
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1936 May]; Telegram
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1936 Jul 9; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1936 Jul 16; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1936 Jul 24; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1936 Aug 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1936 Aug 24; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1936 Sep 12; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1936 Oct 14; Telegram
  - Burton Rascoe to Mr. and Mrs. James Branch Cabell, 1936 Oct 14; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1936 Nov 13; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1936 Nov 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/encl. note with a page proof of Smire, 1936 Nov 22; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1936 Dec 1; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1936 Dec 7; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1936 Dec 14; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1936 Dec 21; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1937 Feb 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1937 Mar 29; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1937 Apr 9; TLS, 3 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1937 May 24; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1937 Oct 25; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1938 Jan 21; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1938 Feb 1; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1938 Mar 1; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1938 Mar 2; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1938 Mar 27; TLS, 3 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1938 Apr 25; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/encl. 3 pp. TLS, Dec 2, Rascoe to Henry Allen Moe, 1938 Nov 31; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1939 Jan 12; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1940 Jan 22; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1942 Jan 23]; TPCS
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1942 Feb 5; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, w/encl. telegram, Feb 6, Albert [?] to Rascoe, 1942 Feb 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1942 Feb 15; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1942 Nov 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1946 Jun 6; TLS, 3 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1947 Oct 11; TLS, 8 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1953 Jul 31; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1953 Aug 10; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1955 Sep 19; TLS, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1955 Oct 8; TLS, 3 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1955 Nov 19; TLS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1955]; TL, 2 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, [1955]; TL, 3 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1956 Sep 28; TLS, 2 p.
- Miscellaneous
  - " Burton Rascoe Visits James Branch Cabell in Virginia" (reproduced), 1953 Jul 26; TMs, 5 p.
  - Notes by Burton Rascoe on jargon, n.d.; TMs, 2 p.
  - 6 clippings of articles by Burton Rascoe, w/covering note, 1918-[n.d.]; Clippings